journalpost.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Journal Post

Your privacy is important to Journal Post. We respect any and all information we collect from you, and are keen to inform you as to how your data is used. You can find all information pertaining to your personal data in this policy.

 **Last Updated:** May 30, 2018.

  1.  **  About Us and Our Privacy Policy**

This policy is written by Journal Post Inc. for all users of its website, app, and any other services. Wherever this policy mentions Journal Post or ‘We’, it refers to Journal Post Inc. and all of its services. When it mentions ‘You’, ‘User(s)’ or ‘Viewer(s)’, it refers to any and everyone making use of our services. We reserve the right to make changes to this policy at any time, and users must take the responsibility to keep themselves updated by regularly visiting this page (though registered users will be notified of changes via email); continued usage of our services will be considered equal to agreement to the terms of this privacy policy.

This policy covers only our own products and services, and does not apply to external websites we may link to. We have no control over and take no responsibility of the data usage of third parties we do not own; their privacy practices and policies must be separately accessed.

  2.  **  Information We Collect From Users**

Journal Post may collect the following information from you:

  *  **  Personal data that directly identifies you **(referred to in this policy as Direct Data) **.** Journal Post does not require any visitor to register as a mandatory part of using its services. However, users have the option of registering with us for heightened convenience and additional services. In the case that a user is registered with us, we may ask for your personal data, including your name, email address, demographic information, preferences, and interests. Users can choose not to give us this information, though this will inhibit the registration. We collect this information only to improve our services according to your preferences, or to update you – with your consent – with updates about our products and services. Personal user data is safe with Journal Post and is not shared with any third parties.
  *  **Log data that indirectly identifies you** (referred to in this policy as Indirect Data) **.** When you visit our website, we automatically receive information about your web browser, internet protocol (IP) address, geo-location, time zone, browsing device, and operating system. We may also receive standard user behavior data provided by your browser and cookies (see Section 7) and your linked social media. This may include online behavior, including the pages you visit, your content preferences, and your interaction with advertisements. This is known as non-indentifying or log data, since it does not identify you as a person, but tells us who you are as an Internet user. This automatically received information will depend on the privacy policies of the related third-parties, for example, the social media websites you use or the manufacturer of your device or operating system.
  *  **Location data.** We may collect geographical location data. This tells us where you are based, including your country, your city, and your language preference. The collected geo-data may be collected to other information automatically obtained from you.
  *  **Financial data.** If you make a purchase from Journal Post – or through Journal Post in case you use an affiliate link for a purchase – we may collect financial information and transactional data. Payments are processed through a secure connection, and related information is collected only for payment details and records, and is not shared with third parties.

  3.  **  How We Collect Data**

All information is collected through lawful means, and always with the user’s consent. You are also free to refuse our requests to collect information from you, though this may render us unable to provide you with some or all of our services.

  *  **Direct information.** We receive direct information when you register with us, subscribe to your services or newsletters, actively opt in for marketing and updates, publish comments on our posts, take part in surveys, make purchases from or through us, or contact us for customer support or otherwise.
  *  **Automatically collected information.** Above mentioned indirect information (see Section 2.2) is collected automatically when you interact with any of our services.
  *  **Third party data.** External sources may provide us with your personal or log data. These may include advertisement networks, analytics providers, and affiliate partners.
  *  **Social media data.** When you access our website through a social media profile like Facebook, we will automatically collect certain public information, like your name, display photo, email address, and Facebook ID. This is in accordance with Facebook’s policies as well as your Facebook privacy settings.

  4.  **How We Store Your Data**

All data is stored where we operate (United States), as well as wherever our partners and affiliates operate. By continuing to use our services, you consent to your data being transferred between legal partners located within different jurisdictions.

  5.  **How We Protect Your Data**

  *  **Data retention.** We retain all of this data only until we need it to provide a service, or use it to improve future services. As long as data is stored, it is protected with full commitment. If your data is no longer required, some of it may still be retained – although entirely anonymously – solely for our research and performance record purposes.
  *  **Data guarding.** We use all commercially acceptable and affordable means to prevent loss, theft, unauthorized access, copying, or modification of data. However, no method of online and electronic storage and usage is 100% safe and secure, and we can therefore not guarantee absolute and complete security and no data breaches. If a breach does occur, users will be notified as legally required. Moreover, Journal Post does not sell or rent, and never has sold or rented, personal user data to any third parties or marketers.
  *  **Limited access.** Journal Post employees, agents and third parties have limited access to your data, and can access only what is required when it is required. Everyone who shares data with us is subject to legally promising confidentiality.
  *  **Data removal.** If you wish for your data to be deleted due to security concerns or if you feel like it is no longer relevant because you decide to stop using our services, you may contact us to remove it from our system. However, if you decide to resume the usage of our services, data will be collected and used as specific in this policy.

None of the above mentioned data is publicly or individually disclosed, though we may share anonymous and aggregated versions of this data. This may include performance reports, website statistics, usage trends, etc.

  6.  **How We Use Your Data**

Journal Post ensures that all collected data is used only for purposes made clear in this privacy policy. If the data is used for any other purposes, users will be notified of the purpose as well as the legal grounds necessitating the usage. We generally use the obtained data, including both directly identifying and indirectly identifying information, to understand who our users and visitors are, how they use our services, and what they prefer with regards to our services. This is then used to improve user experience of our services. The following are specific ways Journal Post uses your personal and log data:

  *  **To recognize and analyze behavior.** Data that indirectly identifies you, through log information and cookies, may be used to analyze your online behavior and to attribute it to you as an individual internet user. This may then be used to make your preferred content more visible and accessible to you. Your usage of Journal Post’s services may be added to this behavioral data to further provide automatically customized content.
  *  **To identify and analyze feedback.** If you leave comments on our website, post reviews, or directly contact our customer support, we may use your personal data, including your name and email address, to analyze individual feedback as well as to reach out to you, if needed.
  *  **To provide you with services registered for.** Direct data may be used to deliver to you the services you have signed up for. This may include newsletters, notifications, and other subscription material. You may also be contacted in case of financial transactions carried out with Journal Post, for the purposes of confirmation, processing and post-purchase information and services.
  *  **To communicate about services, updates and regulations.** Direct data may be used to provide you with information about our services, updates to our policies, and any changes or additions to regulations that relate to your usage of our services. Journal Post is legally required to provide information about changes to policies and regulations, though information about our services may be opted out of.
  *  **To deliver promotional content.** Direct data may be used to communicate promotional content we believe may be of interest to you. This may include offers on our content and other services, discounts on our products, or other sweepstakes, prize draws, competitions or contests run on our websites or apps. You may unsubscribe from receiving promotional content at any time.
  *  **To publish and tailor content and other services.** Direct and indirect data from users, both individually and aggregated, may be used to analyze Journal Post’s content and other services, in order to improve them for users. This is a continuous process, since user behavior like the pages visited, time spent on certain pages, articles or ads clicked on, and products purchased, all provide us with information on what users like to see and best respond to.
  *  **To service and analyze advertisements.** Your indirect data may be used to tailor advertisements to you. Direct data may also be used, for example, when you have clicked on certain promotional material in emails, or have personally contacted us with feedback. Data and behavior related to advertisements may be shared with our advertising partners, search engines, or between ad networks.
  *  **To process orders and collect money owed to us.** In case of financial transactions, your financial data is used to process and verify your orders, keep track of them, collect money from you, and carry out post-purchase formalities. This information may be shared between us and affiliate partners you may make purchases from, though it is not shared with any other parties, neither is it used by us or our partners for any purposes other than completing and recording your financial transactions.

  7.  **Who We Share Data With**

Your data, both direct and indirect, is secure with Journal Post. All information shared is specified in this section. Unless otherwise stated, no other information is shared or distributed in any manner. Generally, only indirect data is shared with third-parties, unless otherwise specified in this section. Direct data is not shared, and will not be shared unless the circumstances are exceptional and explicit content is obtained.

  *  **Journal Post entities.** Your direct and indirect data may be shared between Journal Post’s websites, apps and social media pages. This does not include any entities or businesses not registered under Journal Post Inc.
  *  **Data processing third parties.** Data is shared with third parties who process data on your behalf. This includes data analytics, ad networks, and research and marketing services. Direct data may be shared with Google Analytics and Google AMP Client ID API. For further information on the latter and to learn how to control Google’s usage of your data, please check Google’s Privacy Policy.
  *  **Allowed third parties.** Data may be shared with third parties that you have actively consented to share your data with. This may include linked accounts, social media accounts, affiliate websites, or any other parties actively seeking information to use your data stored with Journal Post. Direct marketing messages may be delivered to you by third parties, for example, an affiliate partner, and you should be able to opt out of these. It should be noted that direct marketing from third parties will subject you to their own privacy policies.
  *  **Published user content.** In case you publish any comments on Journal Post, you automatically share your personal data – including your username and email address, if public – with all viewers. These comments may be published on multiple platforms, including our social media pages and apps, and will be visible to all users unless otherwise stated.
  *  **Mergers and transfers.** In the event that Journal Post is sold or transferred, or decides to merge with another company, your data will be shared with the new owners. Registered users will be notified of this change via email. New owners will only be able to use your data as mentioned in this privacy policy, unless it is changed or updated.
  *  **Legal sharing.** We may share any of your data, without your consent, in the event that we are required to do so by law enforcement. However, this will only be done after our analysis and consent. For example, we may choose to disclose information where it is directly relied upon for someone’s safety, crime prevention, or preventing other unethical and/or illegal activity. we will refuse government or law enforcement requests if they are unrelated to stated purposes, ask for unnecessary information, or violate Journal Post’s rights and/or property.

  8.  **International Transfer of EU Data**

Data processing and usage may require for the information of EU users – defined as those residing in the European Economic Area (EEA) – to be transferred and processed internationally. Third parties that data is shared with may also be based outside the EEA. Whenever this transfer takes place, Journal post ensures data is protected as consistently and wholly as it is within the EEA. We ensure our third parties follow our protection standards, and value your information and legal rights as much as we do.

  9.  **Cookie Policy**

Journal Post collects user activity information through small data text files known as ‘cookies’. These files are stored from websites your visit on your computer’s hard drive, and are then transmitted back whenever you visit these websites again. This helps a website identify you as a unique returning user. Journal Post stores and uses cookies in order to understand your usage of our site, and to provide you with content better suited to your preferences.

You may disable cookies through your browser or external tools and add-ons. However, disabling cookies means you may not be able to access all of our features, products, and services. We suggest you keep cookies active, since these are used entirely to enhance user experience. Following are the types of cookies, and other similar web technologies, used by Journal Post.

  *  **Essential and functional cookies**. These are files that are crucial to your experience of our services, and let us enable basic features by recognizing you as a unique user. They allow features like logins, user management, shopping carts, payment processing, etc. They also remember your choices when you browse, for example, remembering login details or auto-filling forms for you.
  *  **Session cookies.** These remember you during the time you spend on our website in one continuous session. They are deleted when you log out or close your browser.
  *  **Analytics cookies.** While analytics tracking cookies do not identify individual visitors, they provide us with aggregated information and usually include the number of visitors to our website, whether they are new or returning users, the time spent on specific pages, other pages visited, and other related information. These are used by Journal Post as well as all other third parties, like Google Analytics, that use data for analysis purposes. They help us manage and improve our performance as well as the features of our website, and allow us to effectively monitor, audit, research, report and respond.
  *  **Social media cookies.** These are used whenever you interact with Journal Post’s content on social media website like Facebook and Twitter. These are recorded by social media websites and may then be sent to Journal Post.
  *  **Consent cookies.** These are used for consent tools added to our website to identify and manage user preferences.
  *  **Advertising cookies.** Allowing us to track and analyze your browsing habits, these cookies tell us which advertisements you are most likely to interact with. They use your browsing history and then group you with users with similar interests, eventually adding you to a certain ad targeted group. They may also store your IP address, so as to show you advertisements related to your location, wherever possible. Finally, they show you products and services that you are likely to be interested in.
  *  **Third party cookies.** Ad partners and affiliate partners may also use cookies to collect information from you. These cookies are then used to service personalized ads both on Journal Post as well as on the websites of the said affiliate partners.
  *  **Flash cookies.** These are placed into the Adobe Flash plug-in, and are used to automatically enable the Flash feature when you revisit our website, provided that you have previously provided us with permission to run it.
  *  **Pixel tags.** A web technology similar to cookies, pixel tags are small graphic files that allow us, and third parties like ad networks, to record and collect user information. They collect the IP address, the page visited, duration of the visit, and the browser that visited the page. They may also tell us the links you clicked and other actions you took while using our website. They then enable us to analyze this information to both record trends and serve relevant ads.

To read about cookies in more detail, we suggest you inform yourself through [AllAboutCookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

  10.  **User Rights and Responsibilities**

In addition to being thoroughly informed about data usage through this policy, all users are entitled to legal rights they may exercise over their personal data.

  *  **Right to request access and/or transfer.** At any time, you may ask us for a copy of the entire data we have related to you. We will provide you with a copy of personal data and are willing to provide information on how it is being processed. You may also request for your data to be transferred to a third party.
  *  **Right to request correction.** If any information about you in inaccurate, flawed or incomplete, you have the right to request us to correct it.
  *  **Right to withdraw consent and/or request erasure.** For all processing that occurs after active consent, you may withdraw consent at any time. For data that is stored and processed without active consent, continued usage of the website is considered consent. You may halt usage of our services if you wish to. You may also request us to delete all your data stored with it.
  *  **Right to object to/restrict processing**. You can object to us processing your data, though our legal statement and conditions may override your freedoms if you continue to use our services. You may request us to cease using your personal data for direct marketing purposes. Additionally, you may request us to restrict processing your data. This is possible in a number of cases: if you have objecting the processing and we are in the process of determining whether your objection overrides our terms, if the data we possess is inaccurate, if processing of your data is unlawful as an exceptional case, or if we no longer need to hold your data. In case of restriction, your data is not processed anymore, but is not erased.

 _You may exercise these rights, or contact us with privacy queries or complaints, by emailing us at_[ _[email  protected]_](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2252504b5443415b62484d57504c434e524d51560c414d4f) _._
